<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sunk Cost Fallacy on Xing Zhang</title>
    <link>/tags/sunk-cost-fallacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sunk Cost Fallacy on Xing Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Zhang Xing</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sunk-cost-fallacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebate Schemes and the Sunk Cost Fallacy</title>
      <link>/project/museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/museum/</guid>
      <description>Teck-hua Ho, Hang Wu and Xing Zhang
Consumers commit the sunk cost fallacy, a canonical example of irrationality, when their decisions are influenced by costs that have already been incurred and cannot be reversed. Results from field studies on the existence of the sunk cost effect are mixed. In this paper, the authors report a large-scale randomized field experiment involving more than 2,800 museum customers. The authors randomly assigned the participating customers to different rebate schemes and studied the influence of sunk costs on the length of time customers stayed in the museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pay Enough to Go to the Gym</title>
      <link>/project/self-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/self-control/</guid>
      <description>Xing Zhang, Juin Kuan Chong, Ganesh Iyer, and Xiaoyan Xu
This paper examines the role of the sunk cost fallacy as a self-commitment device and its implication for optimal price contract design. Consumers evince the sunk cost fallacy if they condition the consumption level on the sunk cost incurred in the past. Our empirical study suggests that consumers are able to anticipate the fallacy associated with the health club membership fee \textit{ex ante}, and hence they may rationally exploit this fallacy to counteract their future self-control problem in health club attendance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>